[{"question":"How many basic binary subtraction operations are possible?","answers":{"a":"1","b":"4","c":"3","d":"2"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"Full subtractor circuit has","answers":{"a":"3 inputs and 2 outputs","b":"2 inputs and 2 outputs","c":"2 inputs and 3 outputs","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"If A, B and B\u1d62\u2099 are the inputs of a full subtractor,the borrow output is given by","answers":{"a":"A'.B\u1d62\u2099 + B'.B\u1d62\u2099","b":"A'.B\u1d62\u2099 + A'.B + B.B\u1d62\u2099","c":"A.B.B\u1d62\u2099 + A.B'.B\u1d62\u2099","d":"A.B'.B\u1d62\u2099 + A.B.B\u1d62\u2099'"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"A full subtractor can be implemented by using","answers":{"a":"Basic logic gates","b":"Multiplexer","c":"Demultiplexer","d":"All of the above"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"What is a multiplexer?","answers":{"a":"It is a type of decoder which decodes several inputs and gives one output","b":"A multiplexer is a device which converts many signals into one","c":"It takes one input and results into many outputs","d":"It is a type of encoder which decodes several inputs and gives one output"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"In a multiplexer, the selection of a particular input line is controlled by","answers":{"a":"Data controller","b":"Selection lines","c":"Logic gates","d":"Both data controller and selection lines"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"The commercial dual 4-to 1 multiplexer integrated circuit in the TTL family is","answers":{"a":"74951","b":"74153","c":"74154","d":"74151"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"Dual 4-to-1 multiplexer IC 74153 has ________ selection lines.","answers":{"a":"2 common","b":"2 individual","c":"4 common","d":"4 individual"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"Dual 4-to-1 multiplexer IC 74153 has 2 individual _________","answers":{"a":"Outputs","b":"Active low enable inputs","c":"Both opctions A and B","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"In dual multiplexer IC 74153 the selections lines S1 and S0 are present at pin no. ____ and pin no. ____ respectively","answers":{"a":"8, 16","b":"2, 14","c":"6, 15","d":"2, 7"},"correctAnswer":"b"}]
